漫威影业
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供学习  禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
翻译    3ccchange  (Sammy)  丁丁猫哒  haloukeiti
校对     海因里希  草草
时间轴    吉吉和安斯
后期     吉吉
你们是华盛顿来的吗
Are you the guys from Washington?
这地方还有别人来吗
You get many other visitors out here?
你到这儿多久了
How long you been on-site?
早上就到了
Since this morning.
18小时前  一支俄罗斯石油小队发现的
A Russian oil team called it in about 18 hours ago.
之前怎么没发现
How come nobody spotted it before?
没什么好奇怪的
It's really not that surprising.
这里的地貌一直在变
This landscape's changing all the time.
你知道这到底是什么玩意吗
You got any idea what this thing is exactly?
不知道  可能是个气象气球
I don't know. It's probably a weather balloon.
我觉得不是
I don't think so.
我们没有做这种事的专用设备
You know, we don't have the equipment for a job like this.
什么时候才能开始挖
How long before we can start craning it out?
我觉得你还没搞清楚
I don't think you quite understand.
你们需要一架超级起重机
You guys are gonna need one hell of a crane.
基地  我们进去了
Base, we're in.
这是什么
What is this?
小心点
Careful.
中尉
Lieutenant!
-这是什么  -天啊
- What is it? - My God.
基地  帮我接上校
Base, get me a line to the Colonel.
现在是凌晨三点  长官
It's 3:00 a.m., sir.
我才不管现在几点
I don't care what time it is.
他已经等得够久了
This one's waited long enough.
挪威  滕斯贝格
1942年3月
他们来找它了
They've come for it.
以前也有人来过
They have before.
这次不一样
Not like this.
让他们来吧
Let them come.
他们找不到的
They'll never find it.
快打开
Open it!
快点  否则他要...
Quickly, before he...
我花了很久才找到这里
It has taken me a long time to find this place.
你真该获得褒奖
You should be commended.
扶他起来
Help him up.
我觉得你是个很有远见的人
I think that you are a man of great vision.
这点我们很像
And, in this way, we are much alike.
我跟你才不一样
I am nothing like you.
是啊  但其他人看做是迷信的东西
No, of course, but what others see as superstition,
你我却都知道是科学
you and I know to be a science.
你要找的东西不过是传说
What you seek is just a legend.
那又何必这么大费周章地藏它
Then why make such an effort to conceal it?
宇宙魔方是奥丁最珍贵的瑰宝
The Tesseract was the jewel of Odin's treasure room.
这东西不该被埋起来
It is not something one buries.
但我觉得已经很接近了
But I think it is close, yes?
-我帮不了你  -是啊
- I cannot help you. - No.
但也许你能帮帮你的村子
But maybe you can help your village.
那里一定有你的朋友
You must have some friends out there.
可能还有一些小孩子
Some little grandchildren, perhaps?
你不希望他们死吧
I have no need for them to die.
世界树
Yggdrasil.
世界之树
Tree of the world.
守护着智慧
Guardian of wisdom.
还有命运
And fate, also.
元首竟还在沙漠里挖破烂
And the Führer digs for trinkets in the desert.
你并没见过这个  是吧
You have never seen this, have you?
这不是给凡人看的
It's not for the eyes of ordinary men.
没错
Exactly.
下令开火
Give the order to open fire.
蠢货
Fool!
你驾驭不了那种力量
You cannot control the power you hold.
你会业火烧身的
You will burn!
我烧过了
I already have.
迈克尔・奥康纳
O'Connell, Michael.
亨利・卡明斯基
Kaminsky, Henry.
天哪  战死了这么多人
Boy, a lot of guys getting killed over there.
纳粹再夺日托米尔
史蒂文・罗杰斯
Rogers, Steven.
是不是有点让人不想参军了
It kind of makes you think twice about enlisting, huh?
没有
Nope.
罗杰斯
Rogers.
你父亲因什么过世
What did your father die of?
芥子气
Mustard gas.
一战时流行的生化武器
他曾服役于107步兵团
He was in the 107th Infantry.
-我也希望能被指派到...  -你母亲呢
- I was hoping I could be assigned... - Your mother?
她是结核病房的护士
She was a nurse in a TB ward.
她被传染了  没挺过去
Got hit. Couldn't shake it.
病例汇总哮喘
猩红热
风湿热
鼻炎
慢性或急性伤寒
高血压
心悸
乏力
心脏病
精神紧张
曾在家接触到肺结核病毒
近亲患有糖尿病
对不起  孩子
Sorry, son.
给我个机会吧
Look, just give me a chance.
光哮喘这一项就不行
You'd be ineligible on your asthma alone.
你就不能做些什么吗
Is there anything you can do?
我在做
I'm doing it.
我在救你
I'm saving your life.
不合格
战火继续肆虐欧洲
War continues to ravage Europe.
但援兵即将赶到
But help is on the way.
所有健康的适龄青年都准备参军报国
Every able-bodied young man is lining up to serve his country.
就连小蒂米也出力了
Even little Timmy is doing his part
帮忙收集废金属
collecting scrap metal.
干得好  蒂米
Nice work, Timmy!
谁关心这个
Who cares?
赶紧放电影
Play the movie already!
放尊重点
Hey, you wanna show some respect?
与此同时  在海外战场上
Meanwhile, overseas,
勇敢的士兵们正让轴心国明白
our brave boys are showing the Axis powers
为了自由他们愿付出一切
that the price of freedom is never too high.
得了  快放电影
Let's go! Get on with it!
快放动画片
Hey, just start the cartoon!
你给我闭嘴
Hey, you wanna shut up?
只要盟军齐心协力
Together with Allied forces,
就能迎战一切大小威胁
we'll face any threat, no matter the size.
你就是不知道何时该放弃  是吧
You just don't know when to give up, do you?
我可以和你耗一整天
I can do this all day.
要打去找个块头一样大的
Pick on someone your own size.
有时候我觉得你就是喜欢挨揍
Sometimes I think you like getting punched.
我就要打败他了
I had him on the ropes.
这都第几次了
How many times is this?
这次是帕拉默斯人了
You're from Paramus now?
你知道在征兵表上造假是违法的吗
You know it's illegal to lie on the enlistment form.
居然还是新泽西
And seriously, Jersey?
你接到命令了吗
You get your orders?
107步兵团
The 107th.
詹姆斯・巴恩斯中士
Sergeant James Barnes,
明早起航开赴英国
shipping out for England first thing tomorrow.
我也该一起去
I should be going.
来吧  哥们
Come on, man.
我出发前的最后一晚
My last night!
得先帮你收拾一下
I got to get you cleaned up.
怎么  我们要去哪
Why? Where are we going?
未来
The future.
明日世界博览会
我没觉得有什么问题
I don't see what the problem is.
你就要成为纽约仅剩的适龄男子了
You're about to be the last eligible man in New York.
这里可有350万的女人呢
You know there's three and a half million women here?
有一个我就满足了
Well, I'd settle for just one.
好在我已经搞定了
Good thing I took care of that.
巴基
Hey, Bucky!
你怎么和她说我的
What'd you tell her about me?
都是好话
Only the good stuff.
欢迎来到现代奇观展馆
Welcome to the Modern Marvels Pavilion
以及明日世界
and the World of Tomorrow.
更强大的世界
A greater world.
更美丽的世界
A better world.
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
开始了
It's starting!
女士们先生们  有请霍华德・斯塔克先生
Ladies and gentlemen, Mr. Howard Stark!
我爱你  霍华德
I love you, Howard!
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
要是我告诉你  就在短短几年后
what if I told you that in just a few short years,
你的汽车就再也不用碰到地面呢
your automobile won't even have to touch the ground at all?
是的
Yes.
谢谢  曼蒂
Thanks, Mandy.
凭借斯塔克的反重力科技
With Stark Gravitic Reversion Technology
这将成为可能
you'll be able to do just that.
我的神啊
Holy cow.
我说了还要再过几年  是吧
I did say a few years, didn't I?
美国军队需要你  马上参军
史蒂夫  我们请这俩姑娘去...
Hey, Steve, what do you say we treat these girls...
美国三军招募处
走吧  大兵
Come on, soldier.
走吧  你不来还叫什么双人约会
Come on. You're kind of missing the point of a double date.
我们带她们去跳舞
We're taking the girls dancing.
你去吧  我一会儿来找你们
You go ahead. I'll catch up with you.
你真要再试一次吗
You're really going to do this again?
反正这是嘉年华  我碰碰运气
Well, it's a fair. I'm gonna try my luck.
这次又是哪  俄亥俄州吗
As who, Steve from Ohio?
他们会发现的  要是他们收了你就更糟
They'll catch you. Or worse, they'll actually take you.
我知道你觉得我不行
Look, I know you don't think I can do this.
这可不是后巷里打架  史蒂夫  这是打仗
This isn't a back alley, Steve. It's war.
-我知道这是打仗  -你为什么非要去参战
- I know it's a war. - Why are you so keen to fight?
还有很多重要工作呢
There are so many important jobs.
-你觉得我该干什么  开着小红车去收废铁吗  -对
- What do you want me to do? Collect scrap metal in my little red wagon? - Yes.
-有何不可  -我不想去工厂  巴基
- Why not? - I'm not gonna sit in a factory, Bucky.
巴基  拜托了
Bucky, come on.
大家都在战场上拼命
There are men laying down their lives.
我不能躲在后方
I got no right to do any less than them.
你就是不明白
That's what you don't understand.
我不是为了自己
This isn't about me.
是啊
Right.
你不是想证明自己
'Cause you got nothing to prove.
中士  我们还去跳舞吗
Hey, Sarge! Are we going dancing?
当然了
Yes, we are.
别干傻事  等我回来
Don't do anything stupid until I get back.
我怎么会
How can I?
你把傻气都带走了
You're taking all the stupid with you.
臭小子
You're a punk.
混球
Jerk.
小心点
Be careful.
等我到了再取得胜利
Don't win the war till I get there!
来吧  姑娘们  我们去跳舞
Come on, girls. They're playing our song.
在这儿等着
Wait here.
有问题吗
Is there a problem?
在这儿等着就是
Just wait here.
伪造征兵资料是违法的
谢谢
Thank you.
这么说
So,
你想去国外
you want to go overseas.
杀纳粹吗
Kill some Nazis.
你说什么
Excuse me?
我是亚伯罕・厄斯金博士
Dr. Abraham Erskine.
我代表战略科学军团
I represent the Strategic Scientific Reserve.
史蒂夫・罗杰斯
Steve Rogers.
你是哪里人
Where are you from?
皇后区
Queens.
73街和乌托邦大道
73rd Street and Utopia Parkway.
在那之前  是德国人
Before that, Germany.
-这让你不安吗  -没有
- This troubles you? - No.
你又是哪里人  罗杰斯先生
Where are you from, Mr. Rogers?
是纽黑文市
Is it New Haven?
还是帕拉默斯
Or Paramus?
五份文件上写了五个不同城市...
Five exams in five different cities.
文件可能拿错了
That might not be the right file.
我感兴趣的不是文件
No, it's not the exams I'm interested in.
而是你尝试了五次
It's the five tries.
但你还没回答我的问题
But you didn't answer my question.
你想去杀纳粹吗
Do you want to kill Nazis?
这是测试吗
Is this a test?
是的
Yes.
我不想杀任何人
I don't want to kill anyone.
但我不喜欢恶霸
I don't like bullies.
不管是哪里来的
I don't care where they're from.
已经有很多大个子参战了
Well, there are already so many big men fighting this war.
或许现在正需要个小个子
Maybe what we need now is a little guy.
我可以给你一个机会
I can offer you a chance.
只是一个机会
Only a chance.
-我接受  -很好
- I'll take it. - Good.
那么小个子是从哪来
So where is the little guy from?
说实话
Actually?
布鲁克林
Brooklyn.
恭喜你
Congratulations,
士兵
soldier.
合格
准备好了吗  佐拉博士
Are you ready, Dr. Zola?
我的仪器需要非常精确的校准
My machine requires the most delicate calibration.
请原谅  我必须万分小心
Forgive me if I seem overcautious.
你确定你的设备
Are you certain that those conductors of yours
能承受得住能量涌
can withstand the energy surge
直到完成转移吗
long enough for transference?
就这件古物来说
With this artifact
我什么都不能确定
I am certain of nothing.
我担心它完全不会有效
I fear it may not work at all.
20%
Twenty percent.
40%
Forty.
60%
Sixty.
稳定在70%
Stabilizing at 70%.
我花了这么多功夫
I have not come all this way
可不是为了安全  博士
for safety, Doctor.
那是什么
What was that?
我要恭喜你  阿尼姆
I must congratulate you, Arnim.
你的设计没有让我失望
Your designs do not disappoint.
虽然还需要稍稍加固
Though they may require some slight reinforcement.
转换过程稳定
The exchange is stable.
太神奇了
Amazing!
我们所收集到的能量
The energy we have just collected
能为我的设计供能
could power my designs.
我所有的设计
All my designs.
这将改变这场战争
This will change the war.
佐拉博士
Dr. Zola,
这将改变整个世界
this will change the world.
准备  演练开始
Ready, exercise!
新兵们  立正
Recruits, attention!
先生们  我是卡特特工
Gentlemen, I am Agent Carter.
我负责监督本部门的所有事务
I supervise all operations for this division.
你的口音怎么回事  维多利亚女王
What's with the accent, Queen Victoria?
我还以为我是为美军效力
I thought I was signing up for the U.S. Army.
你叫什么名字  士兵
What's your name, soldier?
吉尔默・霍奇  女王陛下
Gilmore Hodge, Your Majesty.
上前一步  霍奇
Step forward, Hodge.
右脚再上前一步
Put your right foot forward.
我们要格斗吗
We gonna wrassle?
我会几个你肯定喜欢的招式
'Cause I got a few moves I know you'll like.
卡特特工
Agent Carter!
菲利普斯上校
Colonel Phillips.
看来你和我们的新兵打成一片了
I can see that you are breaking in the candidates.
不错嘛
That's good!
给我从地上爬起来
Get your ass up out of that dirt
然后归队立正站好
and stand in that line at attention
直到有人让你停为止
till somebody comes tells you what to do.
是  长官
Yes, sir!
巴顿将军曾经说过
General Patton has said
"战争依靠武器  但胜利依靠士兵"
that wars are fought with weapons, but they are won by men.
我们会打赢这场仗
We are going to win this war
因为我们有最好的士兵
because we have the best men.
而且他们会越来越好
And because they are going to get better.
好得多
Much better.
战略科学军团
The Strategic Scientific Reserve
是由盟军成立
is an Allied effort
成员都是由自由世界的精英
made up of the best minds in the free world.
我们的目标
Our goal
是建立史上最优秀的军队
is to create the best army in history.
而每支军队都有一个先行者
But every army starts with one man.
罗杰斯  快下来
Rogers! Get off of there!
这周过后  我们就要选出那个人
At the end of this week, we will choose that man.
他将会是第一个
He will be the first
新一代的超级士兵
in a new breed of super-soldier.
罗杰斯  把那根柱子扶起来
Rogers! Get that rifle out of the mud!
而他们  将亲手把阿道夫・希特勒
And they will personally escort Adolf Hitler
送进地狱
to the gates of hell.
跟上  姑娘们
Pick up the pace, ladies!
快跑
Let's go, let's go!
加速
Double time!
快点  跑快点
Come on! Faster! Faster!
动起来
Move!
立定
Squad, halt!
这面旗子说明你们刚跑完一半
That flag means we're only at the halfway point.
第一个拿到旗子的人
First man to bring it to me
就能和卡特特工一起搭车回去
gets a ride back with Agent Carter.
快去
Move, move!
快点  爬上去
Come on! Get up there!
你们就这点能耐吗  这支部队完了
If that's all you got, this army's in trouble!
上去啊  霍奇
Get up there, Hodge!
上啊  爬上去
Come on! Get up there!
17年来都没人能拿到那面旗子
Nobody's got that flag in 17 years!
好了  恢复列队  快点  归队
Now fall back into line! Come on, fall in!
快点  排好队
Let's go! Get back into formation!
罗杰斯
Rogers!
我说归队
I said fall in!
谢了  长官
Thank you, sir.
快点  姑娘们
Faster, ladies! Come on.
我奶奶都比你们有精神  愿她安息
My grandmother has more life in her, God rest her soul.
动起来
Move it!
你不是真想选罗杰斯吧
You're not really thinking about picking Rogers, are you?
不止是想
I'm more than just thinking about it.
他是不二之选
He is the clear choice.
你把个90磅的哮喘病猫
When you brought a 90-pound asthmatic
带进我的基地时
onto my army base,
我没反对  我想管他呢
I let it slide. I thought, "What the hell."
也许你是把他当做小白鼠
Maybe he'd be useful to you, like a gerbil.
-我没想过你会选他  -起来
- I never thought you'd pick him. - Up.
这孩子的胳膊
You stick a needle in that kid's arm,
一根针就能扎穿
it's gonna go right through him.
快点  姑娘们
Come on, girls.
看看他
Look at that.
我看着他都快哭了
He's making me cry.
我需要的素质不是体能上的
I am looking for qualities beyond the physical.
你知道我们为这项目付出多少心血吗
Do you know how long it took to set up this project?
我还不得不对那个
All the groveling I had to do
什么参议员的委员会低声下气
in front of Senator What's-His-Name's committees?
是的  我清楚你付出了多少努力
Brandt. Yes, I know. I am well aware of your efforts.
那就给我点回报
Then throw me a bone.
霍奇通过了所有测试
Hodge passed every test we gave him.
他强壮  动作又快
He's big, he's fast.
他遵守命令  是个士兵
He obeys orders. He's a soldier.
他是个恶霸
He is a bully.
靠善良可打不了胜仗  博士
You don't win wars with niceness, Doctor.
打胜仗  靠的是胆量
You win wars with guts.
有手榴弹
Grenade!
快跑
Get away!
别过来
Get back!
是假手榴弹
It was a dummy grenade.
警报解除  归队
All clear. Back in formation.
这是测试吗
Is this a test?
他还是太瘦弱了
He's still skinny.
-我能进来吗  -当然
- May I? - Yeah.
睡不着吗
Can't sleep?
可能是紧张吧
I got the jitters, I guess.
我也是
Me, too.
我能问个问题吗
Can I ask you a question?
就一个吗
Just one?
为什么选我
Why me?
这的确是唯一重要的问题
I suppose that is the only question that matters.
这个产自奥格斯堡[德国城市]
This is from Augsburg.
我的故乡
My city.
很多人都忘了
So many people forget that
纳粹第一个侵略的就是自己的国家
the first country the Nazis invaded was their own.
一战结束后
You know, after the last war,
我的同胞们生活得非常艰苦
my people struggled.
他们感到无能为力
They felt weak. They felt
渺小  然后希特勒出现了
small. And then Hitler comes along
阅兵  集会  党旗  大肆宣扬煽动
with the marching and the big show and the flags.
他听说了我
And he hears of me.
还有我的工作  他找到了我
My work. And he finds me.
他说  你
And he says, "You."
你要让我们变强
He says, "You will make us strong."
我并不感兴趣
Well, I am not interested.
于是他派来了他的研究部门
So he sends the head of Hydra,
九头蛇的主管
his research division.
那是位天才科学家  叫约翰・施密特
A brilliant scientist by the name of Johann Schmidt.
施密特已经是核心成员了
Now, Schmidt is a member of the inner circle.
他野心勃勃
And he is ambitious.
他和希特勒一样痴迷于
He and Hitler share a passion for
超能力和日耳曼神话
occult power and Teutonic myth.
希特勒用他的幻想煽动他的追随者
Hitler uses his fantasies to inspire his followers.
而对施密特来说那不是幻想
But for Schmidt, it is not fantasy.
对他来说  那是真的
For him, it is real.
他相信
He has become convinced
这世上隐藏着一股强大的力量
that there is a great power hidden in the earth,
是众神留下的
left here by the gods,
有待一个更优越的人去发现
waiting to be seized by a superior man.
所以当他得知我血清配方的能耐
So when he hears about my formula and what it can do,
他无法抗拒
he cannot resist.
施密特决心成为那个优越者
Schmidt must become that superior man.
他变强了吗
Did it make him stronger?
是的
Yes.
不过也有副作用
But there were other effects.
血清当时尚未调整好
The serum was not ready.
但更重要的是
But more important,
使用的人
the man.
血清能增强人的各个方面  所以
The serum amplifies everything that is inside, so
好的变得更好
good becomes great.
坏的则变得更坏
Bad becomes worse.
所以我选择了你
This is why you were chosen.
因为力量与生俱来的强者
Because a strong man who has known power all his life
可能会失去对力量的敬畏
may lose respect for that power,
但弱者
but a weak man
才懂得力量的价值
knows the value of strength.
并且有
And knows
同情心
compassion.
谢谢...吧
Thanks. I think.
拿来
Give this.
不管明天发生什么  答应我一件事
Whatever happens tomorrow, you must promise me one thing.
永远保持真我
That you will stay who you are.
不是一个好兵
Not a perfect soldier,
而是
but
一个好人
a good man.
敬小个子们
To the little guys.
慢着  我这是干什么
No, no. Wait, wait. What I am doing?
不行  你明天要做手术
No, you have procedure tomorrow.
不能喝酒
No fluids.
好吧  那我们之后再喝
All right. We'll drink it after.
不  我明天又不用做手术
No, I don't have procedure tomorrow.
我不用等  我现在就喝
Drink it after? I drink it now.
你有什么特别需要吗
Is there something in particular you need?
我听说你找到他了
I understand you found him.
你自己看吧
See for yourself.
你不赞成吗
You disapprove.
我只是不明白你为什么要在意他
I just don't see why you need concern yourself.
他不可能成功
I can't imagine he will succeed.
再次成功
Again.
血清是同盟国最后的防线
His serum is the Allies' only defense
能抗衡我们如今掌握的力量
against this power we now possess.
若是我们将其摧毁  就能确保胜利
If we take it away from them, then our victory is assured.
那要我下令吗
Shall I give the order?
我已经下令了
It has been given.
很好
Good.
佐拉博士
Dr. Zola!
你觉得怎样
What do you think?
真是杰作
A masterpiece.
这个街区我很熟悉
I know this neighborhood.
我在那条巷子里被打过
I got beat up in that alley.
还有那个停车场
And that parking lot.
还有那个餐厅后面
And behind that diner.
你是不赞同逃跑吗
Did you have something against running away?
你要是跑了一次  就会一直跑下去
You start running, they'll never let you stop.
而你要是站起来反击
You stand up, you push back.
总有一天会有机会的吧
They can't say no forever, right?
这我略有体会
I know a little of what that's like,
总是被拒绝的感觉
to have every door shut in your face.
我不能理解你为什么要参军
I guess I just don't know why you'd want to join the Army
你是位漂亮的姑娘
if you were a beautiful dame.
我是说漂亮的女人
Or a beautiful... A woman.
是特工  不是姑娘
An agent. Not a dame.
你是很漂亮  但是
You are beautiful, but...
你完全不知道该怎么跟女人搭讪  是吧
You have no idea how to talk to a woman, do you?
这大概是我和女人的最长一次对话了
I think this is the longest conversation I've had with one.
她们不怎么愿意
Women aren't exactly lining up
和一个比她们矮一头的男人跳舞
to dance with a guy they might step on.
你肯定跳过舞吧
You must have danced.
我一直不敢邀女人跳舞
Well, asking a woman to dance always seemed so terrifying.
而这几年来
And the past few years, it just
这事似乎也没那么重要了
didn't seem to matter that much.
我就想不如等等
I figured I'd wait.
等什么
For what?
合适的舞伴
The right partner.
这边走
This way.
我们来这儿干什么
What are we doing here?
跟我来
Follow me.
布鲁克林古董店
今早的天气很棒吧
Wonderful weather this morning, isn't it?
是啊  但我总带着伞
Yes, but I always carry an umbrella.
早上好
Good morning.
拜托  别拍
Please, not now.
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
很好
Good.
脱掉衬衣和领带  摘掉帽子
Take off your shirt, your tie, and your hat.
布兰德参议员  很高兴你能来
Senator Brandt, glad you could make it.
我到底来这儿干什么来了
Why exactly am I in Brooklyn?
我们需要使用城市电网
We needed access to the city's power grid.
当然  如果你肯把我申请的发电机批下来
Of course, if you'd given me the generators I requisitioned...
很多人都在申请经费  上校
A lot of people are asking for funds, Colonel.
这位是克雷...
This is Clem...
弗莱德・克雷姆森  国务院的
Fred Clemson, State Department.
如果你们的项目获得成功
If this project of yours comes through,
我们希望它不仅仅成为轰动新闻
we'd like to see it used for something other than headlines.
老天爷
Jesus.
给那孩子吃点东西吧
Somebody get that kid a sandwich.
舒服吗
Comfortable?
有点大
It's a little big.
那酒有没有给我留
You save me any of that schnapps?
没留多少
Not as much as I should have.
不好意思  下次吧
Sorry. Next time.
斯塔克先生
Mr. Stark,
电力水平如何
how are your levels?
-100%  -很好
- Levels at 100%. - Good.
我们可能会用掉布鲁克林一半电力
We may dim half the lights in Brooklyn,
但我们准备好了
but we are ready
不能更好了
as we'll ever be.
卡特特工
Agent Carter?
你去控制室里会不会更好点
Don't you think you would be more comfortable in the booth?
-好的  抱歉  -好
- Yes, of course. Sorry. - Good.
能听到吗  这开了吗
Do you hear me? Is this on?
女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
今天我们不是进一步走向灭绝
today we take not another step towards annihilation,
而是在和平之路上迈出了第一步
but the first step on the path to peace.
首先是一系列微创注射
We begin with a series of microinjections
将血清注入肌肉群
into the subject's major muscle groups.
血清注入后会立刻引发细胞改变
The serum infusion will cause immediate cellular change.
之后会刺激生长
And then, to stimulate growth,
接着实验对象会接受
the subject will be saturated
生命射线辐射
with Vita-Rays.
感觉还行
That wasn't so bad.
那只是盘尼西林
That was penicillin.
注射血清
Serum infusion
倒计时五秒
beginning in five,
四
four,
三
three,
二
two,
一
one.
开始吧  斯塔克先生
Now, Mr. Stark.
史蒂文
Steven?
能听到我说话吗
Can you hear me?
现在想去厕所是不是有点晚了
It's probably too late to go to the bathroom, right?
继续
We will proceed.
10%
That's 10%.
20%
Twenty percent.
30%
Thirty.
40%
That's 40%.
生命体征正常
Vital signs are normal.
50%
That's 50%.
60%
Sixty.
70%
Seventy.
史蒂文
Steven!
-快关掉  -史蒂文
- Shut it down! - Steven!
快关掉
Shut it down!
关闭反应堆  斯塔克先生
Kill the reactor, Mr. Stark!
关掉  关闭反应堆
Turn it off! Kill it! Kill the reactor!
不
No!
别关
Don't!
我扛得住
I can do this!
80%  90%
Eighty. Ninety.
100%了
That's 100%.
斯塔克先生
Mr. Stark?
史蒂文
Steven.
这小子还真成功了
The son of a bitch did it.
-我做到了  -是的
- I did it. - Yeah, yeah.
我们成功了
I think we did it.
你真的成功了
You actually did it.
感觉怎样
How do you feel?
长高了
Taller.
看起来是高了
You look taller.
现在喜欢布鲁克林了吗  参议员
How do you like Brooklyn now, Senator?
这下柏林的那帮家伙要紧张了
I can think of some folks in Berlin who are about to get very nervous.
祝贺你  博士
Congratulations, Doctor.
谢谢  先生
Thank you, sir.
拦住他
Stop him!
-他们来了  闪开  -快
- They're coming, move it! - Go.
怎么回事  哥们  你没事吧
What are you doing? Buddy, are you all right?
这人中枪了
Hey, this guy's been shot!
我都瞄准他了
I had him!
抱歉
Sorry!
I'm sorry!
不  不  别抓我儿子
No! No! Not my son!
住手
Stop it!
别伤害他
Don't hurt him!
别过来
Get back!
放开我
Let me go!
等等  不要
No, wait, don't!
别伤害他
Don't hurt him!
等等  不要
Wait, don't! Don't!
不要
No! Don't!
去抓他  我会游泳
Go get him! I can swim!
你到底是谁
Who the hell are you?
先头兵
The first of many.
砍掉一颗头
Cut off one head,
会再长出两个
two more shall take its place.
九头蛇万岁
Hail Hydra.
元首可不习惯被无视  施密特先生
The Führer is not accustomed to being ignored, Herr Schmidt.
你承诺为他提供武器  他才资助你的研究
He funds your research because you promised him weapons.
你得听从他的命令
You serve at his pleasure.
因为你负伤  他才将这个研究所奖励给你
He gave you this facility as a reward for your injuries.
奖励  实话实说吧  这是流放
Reward? Call it what it is. Exile.
我不再符合他心目中雅利安人的完美形象
I no longer reflect his image of Aryan perfection.
你觉得这只是外表的问题吗
You think this is about appearances?
你的九头蛇部门未能
Your Hydra division has failed
在超过一年的时间里拿出哪怕一杆来复枪
to deliver so much as a rifle in over a year.
而且我们从当地情报部门获知
And we had learned through local intelligence
你们还向挪威发起了全面入侵
you had mounted a full-scale incursion into Norway.
元首认为  他怎么说的来着
The Führer feels... How does he put it?
不能再继续放纵红骷髅了
"The Red Skull has been indulged long enough!"
先生们
Gentlemen,
你们是来看我们的研究成果的
you have come to see the results of our work.
我给你们展示一下
Let me show you.
希特勒说要让德意志帝国千秋万代
Hitler speaks of a 1,000-year Reich,
事实上却拿不出军队一个月的给养
but he cannot feed his armies for a month.
他的部队在欧洲战场上流血牺牲
His troops spill their blood across every field in Europe,
可他的目标却还是遥遥无期
but still he is no closer to achieving his goals.
这么说你仍想用魔法来打赢战争
And I suppose you still aim to win this war through magic?
是科学  但我理解你的困惑
Science. But I understand your confusion.
强大的力量向来令愚昧之人感到迷茫
Great power has always baffled primitive men.
九头蛇正在建立军火库
Hydra is assembling an arsenal
能将我的敌人一网打尽
to destroy my enemies in one stroke,
不管他们是谁  拥有多少兵力
wherever they are, regardless of how many forces they possess,
只需几个小时就能铲灭
all in a matter of hours.
你的敌人吗
Your enemies?
我的武器具有足够强的破坏力
My weapons contain enough destructive power
能摧毁世界上所有敌国的首都
to decimate every hostile capital on Earth.
简单说  先生们
Quite simply, gentlemen,
我已获得了诸神的力量
I have harnessed the power of the gods.
谢谢  施密特
Thank you, Schmidt.
谢什么
For what?
让我们明白你有多疯狂
For making it clear how obviously mad you are.
柏林也在地图上
Berlin is on this map!
当然了
So it is.
你要为你的傲慢付出代价
You will be punished for your insolence!
你要被带到元首面前...
You will be brought before the Führer himself!
施密特
Schmidt...
抱歉了  博士
My apologies, Doctor,
但我们都知道
but we both knew
在希特勒的阴影下  九头蛇无法壮大
Hydra could grow no further in Hitler's shadow.
九头蛇万岁
Hail Hydra.
Hail Hydra!
九头蛇万岁
抽够了吗
Think you got enough?
重新制造血清的方法
Any hope of reproducing the program
就在你的基因序列里
is locked in your genetic code.
没有厄斯金博士  这得花上好多年
But without Dr. Erskine, it would take years.
他不该就这么死了
He deserved more than this.
如果只能成功这一次
If it could work only once,
他会很自豪是你
he'd be proud it was you.
菲利普斯上校  委员会需要答案
Colonel Phillips, my committee is demanding answers.
好啊  那你先说说怎么有个德国间谍
Great. Why don't we start with how a German spy
坐你的车混进了我的秘密基地
got a ride to my secret installation in your car?
情况怎么样
What have we got here?
虽然谦虚地说
Speaking modestly,
我是本国最好的机械工程师
I'm the best mechanical engineer in this country.
但我也搞不清这东西的构造
But I don't know what's inside this thing
还有它如何运转
or how it works.
我们连这项技术的皮毛都没摸清
We're not even close to this technology.
那谁清楚
Then who is?
九头蛇  你应该看过我们的简报了
Hydra. I'm sure you've been reading our briefings.
我还有很多事要忙  上校
I'm on a number of committees, Colonel.
九头蛇是纳粹的秘密科研部门
Hydra is the Nazi deep-science division.
由约翰・施密特领导
It's led by Johann Schmidt.
不过他有更大的野心
But he has much bigger ambitions.
九头蛇其实是个邪教组织
Hydra is practically a cult.
他们把施密特奉为神  认为他无所不能
They worship Schmidt. They think he's invincible.
那你打算怎么做
So, what are you going to do about it?
今天早上我和总统通过话
I spoke to the President this morning.
从今天起  战略科学军团有了新任务
As of today, the SSR is being retasked.
-上校  -我们要和九头蛇决一死战
- Colonel? - We are taking the fight to Hydra.
收拾行李  卡特特工
Pack your bags, Agent Carter.
你也是  斯塔克
You, too, Stark.
我们今晚就飞往伦敦
We're flying to London tonight.
长官
Sir?
如果你们要对付施密特  我也要加入
If you're going after Schmidt, I want in.
你是个实验品  你得去阿拉莫多[美国城市]
You're an experiment. You're going to Alamogordo.
血清起作用了
The serum worked.
我要的是一支军队  结果却只有你
I asked for an army and all I got was you.
你一个人
You
还远远不够
are not enough.
不是我对上校有意见
With all due respect to the Colonel,
我觉得我们没看到重点
I think we may be missing the point.
我看到了你的能力  史蒂夫
I've seen you in action, Steve.
更重要的是
More importantly,
整个国家都看到了
the country's seen it.
拿报纸来
Paper.
自从你的事迹登报后
The enlistment lines have been around the block
纽约惊现纳粹  神秘人拯救儿童
大街上排满了想入伍的人
since your picture hit the newsstands.
不能让一个偶像级的士兵
You don't take a soldier, a symbol like that,
藏在实验室里
and hide him in a lab.
孩子
Son,
你想去最重要的战场
do you want to serve your country
为国家效力吗
on the most important battlefield of the war?
先生
Sir,
我求之不得
that's all I want.
那恭喜你
Then, congratulations.
你升职了
You just got promoted.
我不知道我行不行
I don't know if I can do this.
这没什么大不了
Nothing to it.
你推销国库券  用来买子弹
You sell a few bonds. Bonds buy bullets.
再用子弹打纳粹
Bullets kill Nazis.
你是美国英雄
You're an American hero.
但这方式跟我想的不一样
It's just not how I pictured getting there.
参议员在国会很有势力
The Senator has got a lot of pull up on the Hill.
你和我们一起好好干
You play ball with us,
很快就能领导自己的队伍了
you'll be leading your own platoon in no time.
拿上盾
Take the shield.
上吧
Go.
是谁强壮勇敢
Who's strong and brave
拯救美国  免遭侵略
Here to save the American way?
不是所有人都能突袭海滩
Not all of us can storm a beach
或开动坦克
or drive a tank.
但我们仍有办法参与战斗
But there's still a way all of us can fight.
是谁挺身战斗
Who vows to fight like a man
为了正义  日夜不休
For what's right, night and day?
E系列国防债券
Series E Defense Bonds.
你每买一张
Each one you buy
战士们的枪膛里就会多一颗子弹
is a bullet in the barrel of your best guy's gun.
是谁为国奔走
Who will campaign door-to-door for America?
高抗大旗  四处巡回
Carry the flag shore to shore for America?
从霍博肯到斯波坎
From Hoboken to Spokane
他胸前闪耀美国星  运筹帷幄
The star-spangled man with a plan
停
Cut.
各位  别看镜头
Guys, don't look at the camera.
不能忘记  威胁仍在  胜利未达
We can't ignore there's a threat and a war we must win
你每买一张战士们的枪膛里就会多一颗子弹
Each one you buy is a bullet in the barrel of your best guy's gun.
是谁会去柏林吊死纳粹
Who'll hang a noose on the goose-stepping goons from Berlin?
是谁会响应美国的召唤
Who will redeem Heed the call for America?
是谁为了人民
Who'll rise or fall
为国献身
Give his all for America?
是谁将证明我们的能力
Who's here to prove that we can?
他胸前闪耀美国星  运筹帷幄
The star-spangled man with a plan
这都是为了赢得战争
We all know this is about trying to win the war.
而要赢  我们就需要子弹和绷带
We can't do that without bullets and bandages,
坦克和帐篷
tanks and tents.
这就是需要你们的地方
That's where you come in.
你买的每一张国债  都能保护你爱的人
Every bond you buy will help protect someone you love.
快看身后
Turn around!
-他在你后面  -让我们的士兵做好万全准备
- He's right behind you! - Keep our boys armed and ready,
德国人就不敢来招惹我们
and the Germans will think twice about trying to get the drop on us.
健壮  坚定又忠心
Stalwart and steady and true
水牛城
密尔沃基
费城
芝加哥
势不可挡  时刻准备保卫美国
Forceful and ready to defend the red, white, and blue
美国队长
是谁将打败轴心国  如狐狸一样聪明
Who'll give the Axis the sack and is smart as a fox?
像雄鹰一样高飞
Far as an eagle will soar
是谁让希特勒不敢踏出自己的地盘
Who's making Adolf afraid to step out of his box?
他知道我们为何而战
He knows what we're fighting for
是谁唤醒了沉睡在美国的巨人
Who waked the giant that napped in America?
我们知道  他就是美国队长
We know it's no one but Captain America
是谁将完成使命
Who'll finish what they began?
是谁将把德国佬踢回日本
Who'll kick the Krauts to Japan?
纽约市
他胸前闪耀美国星
The star-spangled man
运筹
with a
帷幄
plan!
都有谁准备好帮我去修理希特勒了
How many of you are ready to help me sock old Adolf on the jaw?
好吧
Okay.
意大利  1943年11月
距前线五英里处
有志愿者吗
I need a volunteer.
不志愿的话我怎么会在这儿
I already volunteered! How do you think I got here?
我们要看妹子
Bring back the girls!
她们好像只唱那一首歌  但是
I think they only know the one song, but
我去问问看
I'll see what I can do.
去吧  甜心
You do that, sweetheart.
你的靴子不错  小仙女
Nice boots, Tinker Bell!
拜托  伙计们
Come on, guys,
我们是一队的
we're all on the same team here.
队长
Hey, Captain!
在这儿签名吧
Sign this!
我们要妹子
Bring back the girls!
别在意  哥们  他们会喜欢你的
Don't worry, pal. They'll warm up to you. Don't worry.
你好  史蒂夫
Hello, Steve.
你在这干什么
What are you doing here?
官方说法  我并不在这儿
Officially, I'm not here at all.
你的表演不错
That was quite a performance.
是啊
Yeah.
我不得不变通了一下
I had to improvise a little bit.
我以前的观众通常都是...
The crowds I'm used to are usually more
-小孩  -我听说你是美国的新希望
- twelve. - I understand you're "America's New Hope."
我每到一个州国债销售额就上升10%
Bond sales take a 10% bump in every state I visit.
是布拉德参议员的主意吧
Is that Senator Brandt I hear?
至少他还让我做这个
At least he's got me doing this.
菲利普斯还想把我关在实验室里呢
Phillips would have had me stuck in a lab.
你只有这两个选择吗
And these are your only two options?
实验室小白鼠或是跳舞的猴子
A lab rat or a dancing monkey?
你本该能做更多事的
You were meant for more than this, you know.
怎么了
What?
我长久以来的梦想
You know, for the longest time, I dreamed about
就是去海外战场
coming overseas
到最前线
and being on the front lines,
为我的国家效力
serving my country.
等到我终于如愿以偿
I finally got everything I wanted
却是穿着紧身衣
and I'm wearing tights.
他们好像刚打了一场恶仗
They look like they've been through hell.
这些士兵最惨
These men more than most.
施密特向阿扎诺派出了一支部队
Schmidt sent out a force to Azzano.
两百名士兵前去迎战
Two hundred men went up against him,
回来的不到五十个
and less than 50 returned.
你的观众里就有剩下的107步兵团的人
Your audience contained what was left of the 107th.
其他人的不是被杀就是被俘
The rest were killed or captured.
107步兵团
The 107th?
怎么了
What?
快走
Come on.
菲利普斯上校
Colonel Phillips.
这不是胸前闪耀美国星  运筹帷幄的人吗
Well, if it isn't the Star-Spangled Man With A Plan.
你今天运筹什么了
What's your plan today?
我要阿扎诺战役的伤亡名单
I need the casualty list from Azzano.
你没资格命令我  小子
You don't get to give me orders, son.
我只想知道有没有
I just need one name,
107步兵团的詹姆斯・巴恩斯中士
Sergeant James Barnes from the 107th.
我待会儿再找你算账
You and I are gonna have a conversation later that you won't enjoy.
拜托告诉我他还活着  长官  BAR
Please tell me if he's alive, sir. B-A-R...
我知道怎么拼
I can spell.
我今天签了很多哀悼信
I have signed more of these condolence letters today
有多少我都记不清了
than I would care to count.
但是  这个名字我有印象
But the name does sound familiar.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
那其他人呢
What about the others?
你们准备去营救吗
Are you planning a rescue mission?
必须以大局为重
Yes, it's called "Winning the war."
但既然你知道他们在哪  为什么...
But if you know where they are, why not at least...
他们在敌阵后方30英里
They're 30 miles behind the lines
得穿过全欧洲戒备最森严的地区
through some of the most heavily fortified territory in Europe.
去营救只会损失更多人
We'd lose more men than we'd save.
我不指望你能理解这些
But I don't expect you to understand that
因为你只是个演节目的
because you're a chorus girl.
我想我能理解
I think I understand just fine.
那去其他地方理解吧
Well, then understand it somewhere else.
如果我没看错海报的话
If I read the posters correctly,
你得在30分钟内赶到其他地方
you got someplace to be in 30 minutes.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
没错
I do.
如果你有什么想说
If you have something to say,
现在最好别说
right now is the perfect time to keep it to yourself.
你想怎么办  走去奥地利吗
What do you plan to do, walk to Austria?
如果必须如此的话
If that's what it takes.
你听到上校说的了  你朋友可能已经死了
You heard the Colonel. Your friend is most likely dead.
但不能确定
You don't know that.
即便如此  他在制定计划  如果他...
Even so, he's devising a strategy. If he detects...
等他计划好了  可能就晚了
By the time he's done that, it could be too late.
史蒂夫
Steve!
你说你觉得我本该能做更多事
You told me you thought I was meant for more than this.
你是真心的吗
Did you mean that?
当然
Every word.
那就让我去
Then you got to let me go.
我还能做更多
I can do more than that.
上台了  姑娘们  5分钟
On stage, girls. Five minutes!
我的头盔呢
Where's my helmet?
有人看到罗杰斯了吗
Anyone seen Rogers?
九头蛇军营在克劳斯堡
The Hydra camp is in Krausberg,
在这两座山脉之间
tucked between these two mountain ranges.
是一个工厂
It's a factory of some kind.
我们应该能把你送到门口
We should be able to drop you right on the doorstep.
尽可能地接近目标
Just get me as close as you can.
你们着陆后会面临大麻烦的
You two are gonna be in a lot of trouble when you land.
-你不也是  -我要去的地方
- And you won't? - Where I'm going,
可以直接对冲我吼的人开枪
if anybody yells at me, i can just shoot them.
他们也会开枪打你的
They will undoubtedly shoot back.
那就希望这玩意有点用吧
Well, let's hope it's good for something.
卡特特工
Agent Carter?
如果我们不是赶时间
If we're not in too much of a hurry,
真该去趟卢塞恩一起吃芝士火锅宵夜
I thought we could stop off in Lucerne for a late-night fondue.
斯塔克是我见过最好的平民飞行员
Stark is the best civilian pilot I've ever seen.
只有他敢飞进这里  有他在是我们走运
He's mad enough to brave this airspace. We're lucky to have him.
那么你们俩  真要去
So, are you two... do you...
芝士火锅吗
...fondue?
这是应答器  准备好就启动
This is your transponder. Activate it when you're ready
我们会根据信号找到你
and the signal will lead us straight to you.
你确定这管用吗
Are you sure this thing works?
它受测试的次数比你还多  伙计
It's been tested more than you, pal.
回来  我们要把你送到门口
Get back here! We're taking you all the way in!
我一跳下去
As soon as I'm clear,
你们赶紧掉头离开这鬼地方
you turn this thing around and get the hell out of here!
你不能命令我
You can't give me orders!
我当然可以
The hell I can't!
我是队长[上尉]
I'm a Captain!
正如你所见
As you can see,
瓦尔基里正在按计划建造
production of the Valkyrie is progressing on schedule,
即使是这种大小的零件
even with components of this size.
将进度提高60%
Increase the output by 60%
其他研究所也一样
and see to it our other facilities do the same.
但这些囚犯  他们恐怕没这力气
But these prisoners, I'm not sure they have the strength.
那就用尽他们的力气  博士
Then use up what strength they have left, Doctor.
工人永远都不会缺
There are always more workers.
现在别烦我
Not now!
告诉你  德国佬
You know, Fritz,
总有一天  老子也会有根棍子
one of these days, I'm gonna have a stick of my own.
两位
Fellas.
你是谁
Who are you supposed to be?
美国队长
I'm Captain America.
你说啥
I beg your pardon?
怎么着  所有人都带走吗
What, are we taking everybody?
我来自夫勒斯诺  老大
I'm from Fresno, Ace.
还有其他人吗
Is there anybody else?
我在找詹姆斯・巴恩斯中士
I'm looking for a Sergeant James Barnes.
工厂里有个隔离病房
There's an isolation ward in the factory,
被带去的人都没回来
but no one's ever come back from it.
好吧
All right.
林木线在西北方  离大门80码
The tree line is northwest, 80 yards past the gate.
你们冲出去  给他们点颜色瞧瞧
Get out fast and give 'em hell.
我找到其他人后去空地跟你们会合
I'll meet you guys in the clearing with anybody else I find.
等等  你知道你在做什么吗
Wait. You know what you're doing?
当然  我揍了阿道夫・希特勒两百多次了
Yeah. I've knocked out Adolf Hitler over 200 times.
你知道怎么用吗
You know how to use that thing?
好吧
Okay.
怎么回事
What is happening?
这可不是别克
Not exactly a Buick.
-这是点火器  -啥
- That one. "Zündung." - Zündung?
快启动  杜根
Get this thing going, Dugan!
我不知道你还会说德语
I didn't know you spoke German.
在霍华德大学上了三学期
Three semesters at Howard,
后来改学了法语  法国妞更俏
switched to French, girls much cuter.
又没叫你报简历
Didn't ask for the resume.
-左边  -上去
- On your left! - Up top!
不  你在干什么
No, no! What are you doing?
我们的士兵不是对手
Our forces are outmatched.
继续走
Keep moving!
拿手榴弹
Grab those grenades!
中士  32557号
Sergeant. Three-two-five-five-seven.
巴基
Bucky?
我的天
Oh, my God.
-你是...  -是我  史蒂夫
- Is that... - It's me. It's Steve.
史蒂夫
Steve?
-来  -史蒂夫
- Come on. - Steve.
我还以为你死了
I thought you were dead.
我还以为你比这矮
I thought you were smaller.
走吧
Come on.
你是怎么回事
What happened to you?
我参了军
I joined the Army.
痛吗
Did it hurt?
有点
A little.
-效果是永久性的吗  -坚持到现在了
- Is this permanent? - So far.
美国队长
Captain America!
我真激动
How exciting!
我可是你的大影迷
I am a great fan of your films!
这么说厄斯金博士还是成功了
So, Dr. Erskine managed it after all.
虽然没什么进步  但是
Not exactly an improvement, but still,
还是很不错
impressive.
你根本无法想象
You've got no idea.
是吗
Haven't I?
不管厄斯金怎么骗你的
No matter what lies Erskine told you,
我才是他最成功的杰作
you see, I was his greatest success!
你没变成这鬼模样吧
You don't have one of those, do you?
你在自欺欺人  队长
You are deluded, Captain.
你假装自己是个普通士兵
You pretend to be a simple soldier,
但其实  你是不敢承认
but in reality, you are just afraid to admit
我们都已经不是人类了
that we have left humanity behind.
跟你不同
Unlike you,
我骄傲地接受了这一点
I embrace it proudly.
毫不畏惧
Without fear!
那你为什么要跑
Then how come you're running?
来  我们走  上去
Come on, let's go. Up.
长官  我们去楼顶吗
Sir? Are we going to the roof?
那我怎么办
What about me?
我要坐哪里
Where will I sit?
别划花我的车  博士
Not a scratch, Doctor.
记住了
Not a scratch.
走  我们一个个过去
Let's go. One at a time.
这儿肯定有绳子
Gotta be a rope or something!
走吧  快离开这儿
Just go! Get out of here!
我不会丢下你的
No! Not without you!
不管了
Hell.
布兰德参议员  很遗憾地告知您
Senator Brandt, I regret to report that
史蒂文・G・罗杰斯队长
Captain Steven G. Rogers
与3日在敌后区域失踪
went missing behind enemy lines on the third.
空中侦察无果
Aerial reconnaissance has proven unfruitful.
因此  我只能宣布罗杰斯队长
As a result, I must declare Captain Rogers
在行动中阵亡  结束
killed in action. Period.
最后一架侦察机回来了
The last surveillance flight is back.
没有活动迹象
No sign of activity.
-去喝杯咖啡吧  下士  -是  长官
- Go get a cup of coffee, Corporal. - Yes, sir.
我们不能把斯塔克怎样  他是富豪
I can't touch Stark. He's rich
还是军队最大的武器承包商
and he's the Army's number one weapons contractor.
-而你则都不是  -恕我直言  长官
- You are neither one. - With respect, sir,
我不后悔我的行为
I don't regret my actions.
我认为罗杰斯队长也不后悔
And I don't think Captain Rogers did, either.
你觉得我在意你的想法吗
What makes you think I give a damn about your opinions?
我给了你个机会  卡特特工
I took a chance with you, Agent Carter.
而现在美国金童
And now America's golden boy
还有很多优秀士兵死了
and a lot of other good men are dead
就因为你喜欢人家
'cause you had a crush.
不是的
It wasn't that.
我是有信念
I had faith.
那等这个部门被关闭的时候
Well, I hope that's a big comfort to you
希望你的信念能给你点安慰
when they shut this division down.
-看是谁回来了  -真不敢相信
- Look who it is! - Can't believe that.
外面怎么回事
What the hell's going on out there?
他们有些人需要医治
Some of these men need medical attention.
医生  有伤员
Medic, we got wounded.
这里
Right over here.
我愿意接受处分
I'd like to surrender myself for disciplinary action.
没这必要
That won't be necessary.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
信念哈
Faith, huh?
你迟到了
You're late.
没法叫车来
Couldn't call my ride.
为美国队长欢呼
Let's hear it for Captain America!
我很荣幸将此英勇勋章
I am honored to present this medal for valor
颁给我的好朋友
to my personal friend,
美国队长
Captain America!
队长  该你出场了
Captain, that's your cue!
我还以为他会更高些
I thought he'd be taller.
美国队长将被颁发英勇勋章
第五个在波兰  波罗的海附近
The fifth one was here in Poland, right near the Baltic.
第六个在...
And the sixth one was
大概
about
这里  马奇诺防线以西三四十英里处
here, 30, 40 miles west of the Maginot Line.
我就瞥了一眼
I just got a quick look.
没有人十全十美嘛
Well, nobody's perfect.
这些是我们已知的武器工厂
These are the weapon factories we know about.
据巴恩斯中士说
Sergeant Barnes said
九头蛇把所有装备都运到了另一个地方
that Hydra shipped all the parts to another facility
而在地图上没有
that isn't on this map.
卡特特工  和军情六处协调
Agent Carter, coordinate with Ml6.
发动所有同盟国去找九头蛇总部
I want every Allied eyeball looking for that main Hydra base.
那我们呢
What about us?
我们去给约翰・施密特一个下马威
We are going to set a fire under Johann Schmidt's ass.
怎么样  罗杰斯
What do you say, Rogers?
你背出了地图  你觉得你能铲除九头蛇吗
It's your map. You think you can wipe Hydra off it?
好  长官
Yes, sir.
我需要一支队伍
I'll need a team.
我们已经在召集最出色的士兵
We're already putting together the best men.
恕我直言  长官
With all due respect, sir,
我也找了
so am I.
是这么回事吗
So, let's get this straight.
我们好不容易逃出来  你又要我们再去吗
We barely got out of there alive, and you want us to go back?
差不多
Pretty much.
听起来很有趣
Sounds rather fun, actually.
我加入
I'm in.
我们也加入
We're in.
我永远乐意战斗
Hell, I'll always fight.
但你得为我做一件事
But you got to do one thing for me.
什么事
What's that?
请客喝酒
Open a tab.
这容易
Well, that was easy.
再来一轮
Another round.
他们怎么喝得下这么多
Where are they putting all this stuff?
是吧  告诉你了
See? I told you.
他们都是笨蛋
They're all idiots.
那你呢
How about you?
你准备跟随美国队长去赴汤蹈火吗
You ready to follow Captain America into the jaws of death?
当然不
Hell, no.
那个布鲁克林来的傻小个子
That little guy from Brooklyn who was too
打起架来从不放弃
dumb not to run away from a fight.
我要跟着他
I'm following him.
你还穿那套紧身衣吗
But you're keeping the outfit, right?
知道吗
You know what?
美国队长  巡演取消
我还真习惯了
It's kind of growing on me.
记住啦  天下没有不散的宴席
And remember that the best of friends must part, must part
再见  再见了
Adieu, adieu...
-队长  -卡特特工
- Captain. - Agent Carter.
女士
Ma'am.
霍华德为你准备了些新装备
Howard has some equipment for you to try.
明早去看看
Tomorrow morning?
好啊
Sounds good.
看来你的精英部队已经准备上阵了
I see your top squad is prepping for duty.
你不喜欢音乐吗
You don't like music?
我喜欢
I do, actually.
没准等战争结束
I might even, when this is all over,
我还会去跳个舞
go dancing.
那我们还等什么
Then what are we waiting for?
合适的舞伴
The right partner.
明早八点  队长
08:00, Captain.
是  女士
Yes, ma'am.
我会到的
I'll be there.
我成小透明了
I'm invisible.
我要变成你了
I'm turning into you.
感觉像个噩梦
It's like a horrible dream.
别太难过了
Don't take it so hard.
也许她还有个闺蜜
Maybe she's got a friend.
发射特征不同寻常
Emission signature is unusual.
A和B射线中性
Alpha and beta ray neutral.
但罗杰斯估计没发现
Though I doubt Rogers picked up on that.
看上去挺无害的
Seems harmless enough.
搞不懂有什么可大惊小怪的
Hard to see what all the fuss is about.
把这记下来
Write that down.
四百余俘虏被解救
打扰一下  我找斯塔克先生
Excuse me. I'm looking for Mr. Stark.
他跟菲利普斯上校在里面
He's in with Colonel Phillips.
你想等的话  当然也可以
Of course, you're welcome to wait.
我
I
在报上看到了你的事迹
read about what you did.
那事儿啊
Oh, the... Yeah.
那只是...
Well, that's, you know.
尽责而已
Just doing what needed to be done.
听上去没那么简单
Sounded like more than that.
你救了近四百人
You saved nearly 400 men.
说真的  没什么大不了
Really, it's not a big deal.
对他们的老婆来说可不是
Tell that to their wives.
我觉得并不是所有人都结婚了
I don't think they were all married.
你是个英雄
You're a hero.
那个嘛...
Well, that you know,
取决于你怎么定义...
that depends on the definition, really.
美国女人
The women of America,
都欠你的情
they owe you their thanks.
而既然她们不在这儿
And seeing as they're not here...
队长
Captain!
大家都在等你  没事的话就快来
We're ready for you, if you're not otherwise occupied.
卡特特工  等等
Agent Carter, wait.
看来找个伴也没那么难
Looks like finding a partner wasn't that hard after all.
佩吉  不是你想的那样
Peggy, that's not what you thought it was.
我什么都没想  队长  完全没有
I don't think anything, Captain, not one thing.
你一直想成为军人  如今得偿所愿
You always wanted to be a soldier, and now you are,
跟其他人没什么两样
just like all the rest.
那你跟斯塔克又算什么
Well, what about you and Stark?
我怎么知道你们有没有...
How do I know you two haven't been
芝士火锅
fondue-ing?
你还是一点都不懂女人
You still don't know a bloody thing about women.
芝士火锅只是奶酪和面包  哥们
Fondue is just cheese and bread, my friend.
真的吗
Really?
我没想到...
I didn't think...
你就不该多想  伙计
Nor should you, pal.
如果你自以为摸透女人了
The moment you think you know what's going on in a woman's head
你就完蛋了
is the moment your goose is well and truly cooked.
我嘛  更注重工作
Me, I concentrate on work,
就现在来说
which at the moment
就是确保你和你的人都不送命
is about making sure you and your men do not get killed.
碳聚合物
Carbon polymer.
应该可以承受德国刺刀
Should withstand your average German bayonet.
但九头蛇可不会用小刀对付你
Although Hydra's not going to attack you with a pocket knife.
我听说你对这个还有了感情
I hear you're kind of attached.
用起来比你想的要顺手
It's handier than you might think.
我给你准备了几个选择
I took the liberty of coming up with some options.
这个很有趣
This one's fun.
里面装了继电器
She's been fitted with electrical relays
-能让你...  -那这个呢
- that allow you to... - What about this one?
不不  那件还未完工
No, no, that's just a prototype.
是什么材质
What's it made of?
振金
Vibranium.
比钢强  重量则只有其三分之一
It's stronger than steel and a third the weight.
它可以完全吸收振动
It's completely vibration absorbent.
为何不作为全军配备
How come it's not standard issue?
这种金属在地球上极为罕见
That's the rarest metal on Earth.
你手中这件
What you're holding there,
是唯一的一个
that's all we've got.
快好了吗  斯塔克先生
You quite finished, Mr. Stark?
队长肯定还有事呢
I'm sure the Captain has some unfinished business.
你觉得如何
What do you think?
行  挺好用的
Yes, I think it works.
我对服装还有些想法
I had some ideas about the uniform.
都听你的  伙计
Whatever you want, pal.
你一直在失败
You are failing!
我们就要发动震撼全球的攻势了
We are close to an offensive that will shake the planet,
现在却一推再推
yet we are continually delayed
就因为你搞不定一个带盾牌的白痴
because you cannot outwit a simpleton with a shield!
这不是我的专长
This is hardly my area of expertise.
我只会发明武器
I merely developed the weapons.
我又不会用
I cannot fire them.
完成你的使命  博士
Finish your mission, Doctor,
别让那美国人先把我们端了
before the American finishes his.
长官
Sir!
我很抱歉  施密特先生
I'm sorry, Herr Schmidt.
我们全军覆灭了
We fought to the last man.
显然还没有全灭
Evidently not.
还记得在科尼岛我逼你玩旋风飞车吗
Remember when I made you ride the Cyclone at Coney Island?
记得  我吐了
Yeah, and I threw up?
这不会是报复吧
This isn't payback, is it?
怎么会呢
Now why would I do that?
你是对的  佐拉博士在火车上
We were right. Dr. Zola's on the train.
九头蛇调度员刚准许了他加速
Hydra dispatcher gave him permission to open up the throttle.
不管他是去哪  他们肯定挺着急
Wherever he's going, they must need him bad.
我们快行动  他们像是赶着去投胎
Let's get going, because they're moving like the devil.
我们只有十秒钟空隙
We only got about a 10-second window.
错过了
You miss that window,
就要被火车撞死了
we're bugs on a windshield.
小心脚下
Mind the gap.
那快走吧  兄弟们
Better get moving, bugs!
拦住他
Stop him!
继续射击
Fire again!
我本来就要打败他了
I had him on the ropes.
我知道
I know you did.
趴下
Get down!
继续射击
Fire again!
快杀了他
Kill him! Now!
巴基
Bucky!
坚持住
Hang on!
抓住我的手
Grab my hand!
不
No!
坐下
Sit down.
这是什么
What is this?
牛排
Steak.
里面是什么
What is in it?
牛肉
Cow.
博士  你知不知道
Doctor, do you realize
这么一块高级牛肉
how difficult it is to get ahold
在这里多难搞到
of a prime cut like that out here?
我不吃肉
I don't eat meat.
-为什么不吃  -吃不惯
- Why not? - It disagrees with me.
氰化物怎么样  也让你肚子不舒服吗
How about cyanide? Does that give you the rumbly tummy, too?
每次我们想活捉九头蛇的特工
Every Hydra agent that we've tried to take alive
都在我们能阻止前服毒自尽了
has crunched a little pill before we can stop him.
可你没有
But not you.
所以  我的绝妙推论是
So, here is my brilliant theory.
你不想死
You want to live.
你是在威胁我  上校
You're trying to intimidate me, Colonel.
我给你带了晚餐
I bought you dinner.
由于他所提供的宝贵信息
"Given the valuable information he has provided
以及作为他大力合作的交换条件
"And in exchange for his full cooperation,
佐拉博士将被送返瑞士
"Dr. Zola is being remanded to Switzerland"?
今早我把消息发去了华盛顿
I sent that message to Washington this morning,
当然是被加密了
of course it was encoded.
你们的人还没解开吧
You guys haven't broken those codes, have you?
不然可就尴尬了
That would be awkward.
施密特不会相信的
Schmidt will know this is a lie.
不管怎样他都会杀了你  博士
He's going to kill you anyway, Doc.
你成了累赘
You're a liability.
你知道最多他的秘密
You know more about Schmidt than anyone.
而且...
And
最后一个被你害死的人
the last guy you cost us
是罗杰斯队长最好的朋友
was Captain Rogers' closest friend,
所以我可不敢说你会受到多好的保护
so I wouldn't count on the very best of protection.
保自己
It's you
还是施密特
or Schmidt.
你只有这两条路
It's just the hand you've been dealt.
施密特坚信他是在追随众神的脚步
Schmidt believes he walks in the footsteps of the gods.
只有得到整个世界他才会满足
Only the world itself will satisfy him.
你也知道他疯了吧
You do realize that's nuts, don't you?
怎么
What?
疯不疯狂已经不重要了
The sanity of the plan is of no consequence.
-为什么  -因为他做得到
- And why is that? - Because he can do it!
他的目标是什么
What's his target?
他的目标
His target
是全世界
is everywhere.
明天
Tomorrow,
九头蛇将会称霸世界
Hydra will stand master of the world,
借瓦尔基里之翼获得胜利
borne to victory on the wings of the Valkyrie.
敌人的武器对我们都不堪一击
Our enemies' weapons will be powerless against us.
若是一架飞机被击落
If they shoot down one plane,
还有数百架飞机会予以猛烈回击
hundreds more will rain fire upon them!
砍掉一颗头
If they cut off one head,
会再长出两个
two more shall take its place.
九头蛇万岁
Hail Hydra.
伦敦地区依然在施行宵禁
Blackout is still in effect throughout the London area.
请等待警报解除
Please wait for the all-clear.
请注意
Your attention, please.
所有市民请待在家里  等待进一步通知
All citizens shall remain indoors until further notice.
伦敦地区依然在施行宵禁
Blackout is still in effect throughout the London area.
厄斯金博士说过
Dr. Erskine said that
血清不光会影响肌肉
the serum wouldn't just affect my muscles,
也会影响细胞
it would affect my cells.
产生一个再生和愈合的保护系统
Create a protective system of regeneration and healing.
也就是说
Which means
我不会醉
I can't get drunk.
你知道吗
Did you know that?
你的新陈代谢速率是常人的四倍
Your metabolism burns four times faster than the average person.
博士觉得那可能是副作用之一
He thought it could be one of the side effects.
那不是你的错
It wasn't your fault.
你看报告了吗
Did you read the report?
看了
Yes.
那你该知道是我害死了他
Then you know that's not true.
你尽力了
You did everything you could.
你相信你朋友吗
Did you believe in your friend?
你尊重他吗
Did you respect him?
那就别再自责
Then stop blaming yourself.
尊重巴恩斯自己的选择
Allow Barnes the dignity of his choice.
他肯定认为值得为你赴汤蹈火
He damn well must have thought you were worth it.
我要抓到施密特
I'm going after Schmidt.
只要九头蛇没被杀绝或逮捕  我就不会罢休
I'm not gonna stop until all of Hydra is dead or captured.
你不是一个人
You won't be alone.
约翰・施密特该被扔进疯人院
Johann Schmidt belongs in a bughouse.
他觉得自己是神
He thinks he's a god,
还要炸掉半个世界  以证明这一点
and he's willing to blow up half the world to prove it,
就从美国开始
starting with the USA.
施密特使用的力量超出我们的能力
Schmidt's working with powers beyond our capabilities.
只要他穿过大西洋
He gets across the Atlantic,
就能在一小时内夷平整个东海岸
he will wipe out the entire Eastern Seaboard in an hour.
我们有多少时间
How much time we got?
据那位新朋友的说法  不到24小时
According to my new best friend, under 24 hours.
他现在人在哪
Where is he now?
九头蛇最后的基地
Hydra's last base is here.
在阿尔卑斯山脉
In the Alps,
地表下五百英尺
500 feet below the surface.
那我们该怎么做
So what are we supposed to do?
又不能直接敲门进去
I mean, it's not like we can just knock on the front door.
怎么不能
Why not?
我们就这么做
That's exactly what we're going to do.
自大也许不是美国人的独有特征
Arrogance may not be a uniquely American trait,
但不得不说你诠释的比别人都出色
but I must say, you do it better than anyone.
然而即便是你
But there are limits
也有做不到的事  队长
to what even you can do, Captain.
还是厄斯金的说法有所不同
Or did Erskine tell you otherwise?
他跟我说你疯了
He told me you were insane.
他嫉妒我天赋异禀
He resented my genius
还企图剥夺本就属于我的东西
and tried to deny me what was rightfully mine.
可他却给了你一切
But he gave you everything.
那么
So,
你有什么特别之处吗
what made you so special?
没有
Nothing.
我就是个布鲁克林的小子
I'm just a kid from Brooklyn.
我可以和你耗一整天
I can do this all day.
你当然可以  当然了
Of course you can, of course.
但可惜的是我有点忙
But, unfortunately, I am on a tight schedule.
我也是
So am I.
罗杰斯
Rogers!
这个你用得着
You might need this!
谢了
Thanks!
我们进去了  立即进攻
We're in! Assault team, go!
行动
Move out!
保持距离
Keep your spacing!
砍掉一颗头  会再长出两...
Cut off one head, two more shall...
那就把这两个也砍掉
Let's go find two more!
停火
Cease fire.
你迟到了
You're late.
你不是要去...
Weren't you about to...
哦对
Right.
目标  纽约市
上来
Get in!
稳住
Keep it steady!
等等
Wait!
去抓到他
Go get him.
我可不会吻你
I'm not kissing you!
芝加哥
纽约市
你就是怎么都不放弃是吧
You don't give up, do you?
没错
Nope!
你本可以拥有神的力量
You could have the power of the gods!
却在胸口挂面国旗
Yet you wear a flag on your chest
就以为在打国家之战了吗
and think you fight a battle of nations!
我已经看见了未来  队长
I have seen the future, Captain!
-未来可没有国旗  -我的未来不是那样的
- There are no flags! - Not my future!
你都干了什么
What have you done?
不
No!
目标  纽约市
回复  我是罗杰斯队长  收到吗
Come in. This is Captain Rogers. Do you read me?
罗杰斯队长  你...
Captain Rogers, what is your...
史蒂夫  是你吗  你没事吗
Steve, is that you? Are you all right?
佩吉  施密特死了
Peggy, Schmidt's dead!
飞机呢
What about the plane?
这个比较难解释
That's a little bit tougher to explain.
告诉我你的坐标  我给你找个安全降落点
Give me your coordinates. I'll find you a safe landing site.
没法安全降落了
There's not gonna be a safe landing.
但我会尝试迫降
But I can try and force it down.
我让霍华德来听  他知道怎么做
I'll get Howard on the line. He'll know what to do.
没时间了
There's not enough time.
这架飞机正飞速冲纽约驶去
This thing's moving too fast and it's heading for New York.
我得让飞机坠海
I got to put her in the water.
求你  别这么做
Please, don't do this.
我们还有时间  能想到办法
We have time. We can work it out.
我现在在无人地带
Right now I'm in the middle of nowhere.
要是不立即行动  会有很多人丧命
If I wait any longer, a lot of people are gonna die.
佩吉
Peggy,
这是我的选择
this is my choice.
佩吉
Peggy?
我在
I'm here.
那支舞得改天再跳了
I'm gonna need a rain check on that dance.
好吧
All right.
下周六  在鹳鸟俱乐部
A week, next Saturday, at the Stork Club.
没问题
You got it.
八点整
8:00 on the dot.
不准迟到
Don't you dare be late.
明白吗
Understood?
我还是不会跳舞
You know, I still don't know how to dance.
我会教你
I'll show you how.
你来就好
Just be there.
我们让乐队演奏点舒缓的曲子
We'll have the band play something slow.
我可不想踩到你的...
I'd hate to step on your...
史蒂夫
Steve?
欧战胜利日
敬队长
To the Captain.
先生
Sir?
去下一个坐标点
Take us to the next grid point.
但这里没有残骸的痕迹
But there's no trace of wreckage.
能量信号也只到这儿了
And the energy signature stops here.
继续找就是了
Just keep looking.
机密  非在职
曲线球  高高地打出界外
Curve ball, high and outside for ball one.
道奇队现在四比四平手
So the Dodgers are tied, 4-4.
观众们都知道  只要他一挥棒
And the crowd well knows that with one swing of his bat,
这位小伙子就能扭转乾坤
this fellow's capable of making it a brand-new game again.
今天埃贝茨球场的比赛太精彩了
Just an absolutely gorgeous day here at Ebbets Field.
费城人队把比分控制在了四比四平
The Phillies have managed to tie it up at 4-4.
而道奇队还有三人在场上
But the Dodgers have three men on.
帕森上月在费城让雷泽吃了瘪
Pearson beaned Reiser in Philadelphia last month.
这位年轻人肯定想回敬他吧
Wouldn't the youngster like a hit here to return the favor?
皮特倾身  投球了
Pete leans in. Here's the pitch.
挥棒  球飞向右方  经过里兹
Swung on. A line to the right. And it gets past Rizzo.
跑三段就能得分
Three runs will score.
雷泽上三垒  杜奇在指挥他上垒
Reiser heads to third. Durocher's going to wave him in.
接球  但他们拼不过他
Here comes the relay, but they won't get him.
早上好
Good morning.
或者该说  下午好
Or should I say afternoon?
天哪
Oh my god.
我在哪
Where am I?
你在纽约市的一间术后恢复室里
You're in a recovery room in New York City.
道奇队以八比四领先了  道奇队
The Dodgers take the lead, 8-4. Oh, Dodgers!
大家都激动得站起来了
Everyone is on their feet.
今天真是场精彩绝伦的比赛啊  各位
What a game we have here today, folks.
真精彩
What a game, indeed.
我到底在哪
Where am I really?
我不太明白你的意思
I'm afraid I don't understand.
这场比赛
The game.
是在1941年5月
It's from May 1941.
我知道  因为我在现场
I know, 'cause I was there.
我再问你一次
Now, I'm going to ask you again.
我到底在哪
Where am I?
-罗杰斯队长  -你是谁
- Captain Rogers... - Who are you?
罗杰斯队长  等等
Captain Rogers, wait!
全体特工注意  紧急警报
All agents, code 13!
重复  全体特工注意  紧急警报
I repeat. All agents, code 13!
别紧张  大兵
At ease, soldier!
我为那场表演表示道歉  但是
Look, I'm sorry about that little show back there, but
我们以为最好让你慢慢知道一切
we thought it best to break it to you slowly.
知道什么
Break what?
你一直在沉睡  队长
You've been asleep, Cap.
睡了大概七十年
For almost 70 years.
你没事吧
You gonna be okay?
没事
Yeah.
没事  只是...
Yeah, I just...
我错过了个约会
I had a date.
美国队长
美国队长将在《复仇者联盟》中回归
睡不着吗
Trouble sleeping?
你有任务要给我吗  长官
You're here with a mission, sir?
是的
I am.
想让我回归这个世界吗
Trying to get me back in the world?
是让你拯救世界
Trying to save it.
明年夏天
你以为这世上就你一个英雄吗
You think you're the only hero in the world?
需要
集结
队伍
先生们
Gentlemen?
该你们上场了
You're up.
复仇者联盟
你真挺有劲
Got a mean swing.
2012年5月